





Summary

Jump to Section

Deputy Manager of Application Support team Nine years of total experience with 7.5 years of experience in Technical and Application Support profile. Specialized in Mcrosoft Azure App Service, Azure Linux and Windows Virtual Machines, Linux Administration, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Oracle 11g. Have excellent ability in scrutinizing problems by log investigation and debugging application code. Excellent business and technical communication (Verbal, Written) and have extensive experience in Customer communication..

Work Experience

• Koch Business Solutions India Private Limited as Sr. Automation Specialist Nov 2020 to Till Date

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

I am working as a Sr. Automation Specialist where my role to make the process structured and handling complex tickets

Ensim India Pvt Ltd (An Ingram Micro Company) as Deputy Manager- Application Support Jun 2016 to Oct 2020

Responsibilities

Deploy the platform in Azure app service for Cloud-based providers and in Linuxenvironment for on-premises providers.

Deploy application and components in Linux and Windows environment along with Database.

Upgrade and apply patches for the platform.

Monitoring the performance of the platform and modifying application configuration for better performance.

Investigating the issue reported by Reseller and end-customers. Work with cross-team in order to provide fix for urgent software issues.

Prepare complex SQL scripts to generate report for the management and BI team.

Sync-up call with Reseller and Customers for the open issues and updates.

Preparing custom technical documentation for resellers and end-customers.

Preparing team KPI report and present the same to the management team.

Project management for the new Reseller on-boarding projects.

Technologies worked on

MS Azure (Azure app service, Azure VM, Monitoring, Network configuration), Linux (RHEL 7), SQL (PostgreSQL and MS SQL Server)

Ticketing system worked on

Freshdesk, Request Tracker (Internal ticketing system), JIRA

Four Loops Solutions Pvt Ltd., as Team Leader- Application Support

1

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Jan 2014 to May 2016

Responsibilities

Deploy platform in Linux (RHEL 6, 7) and MS Windows Server (2008, 2012) for on-premise providers and Azure Linux

VM for Cloud providers. Web server used - Apache Tomcat 7.x, 8.x.

Monitoring and enhancing platform performance

Preparing complex SQL scripts to generate reports for the management team.

Checking ticket queue and being a senior team member, processing the complex tickets and solve them with proper efficiency.

Preparing and managing Knowledge-base articles (create, review, approve, and manage).

Sync-up call with the customers (weekly basis) for issue and update discussions.

Preparing custom technical documents for end-customers based on requirements.

Product training expertise for platform-specific operations.

Technologies worked on

Linux (RHEL 6, 7), Azure app service, Windows Server 2008/2012, Azure VM, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server 2012, Oracle 11g

Ticketing system worked on Zendesk, Bugzilla, JIRA

Ardent Computech Pvt Ltd., as Project Engineer, L&D

May 2011 to Dec 2013

Responsibilities

Provide corporate training on Java SE, Java EE and SQL to the technical students of various streams.

Corporate trainer of Java SE and Java EE for Wipro Technologies under the payroll of Ardent Computech Pvt Ltd. Vocational training expert.

Helping technical students perform various complex projects as their major and minor projects.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: BCA (Computer Application) from West Bengal University of Technology (WBUT) in 2008

PG: MCA (Computer application) from Kalyani University in 2011

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:
ITIL Foundations in IT Service Management
Mcrosoft certified Azure Administrator Associate (AZ-104)

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
SQL		2020	9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
MS SQL SERVER	12	2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
PostgreSQL	9.4	2020	8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Linux	RHEL 7	2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Apache Tomcat	8	2020	7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
AZURE		2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓		✓
Bengali	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: CloudBlue Commerce

Client: Ingram Micro

Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Spain, India Role: Domain Expert Duration: Apr 2017 - Sep 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: Microsoft Azure, Linux Administration, MS SQL Server, Postgresql

Project Details: It is a multi-tier commerce platform that allows Service Providers to launch a marketplace to partners, resellers, and end-customers. Provider can onboard products, design catalog and bill, and invoice with different currencies. The platform also allows us to bundle different types of products and manage multiple tiers of resellers. Overall, this platform provides end-to-end marketplace solutions and can be integrated with external CRM and ERP systems.

Project Title: Cloudblue Connect

O!! - -- - 1 -- --- - 1 # ----

Client: ingram ivicro

Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Spain, Moscow, India

Role: Domain Expert

Skill Used: Microsoft Azure, MS SQL Server, Postgresql

Project Details: It is a catalog and channel management platform that supports omni-product (any type of product) distribution - from technology goods and perpetual license software to Software as a Service (SaaS), Infrastructure as a Service (laaS), and Anything as a Service (XaaS). The platform supports any channel including direct and indirect (tiermodel distribution) as well as internal procurement.

Project Title: Ensim Automation Suite

Client: Ensim Corporation Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: India, USA Role: Domain Expert

Duration: Jan 2013 - Mar 2019 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Duration: Mar 2017 - Sep 2020

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Linux Administration, Windows Server Administration, MS SQL Server, Postgresql, Mcrosoft Azure, Business Communication, Technical Support

Role Description: I was working as a Technical Support specialist for this project where I need to provide Customer support as well as get the requirement from customer, work with Management team members and introduce the new features requested by Customers.

Project Details: It is an automation and orchestration solution for ordering, provisioning, billing, and management of users and organizations for infrastructure, business application, and services.

It enables Service Providers to deploy a complete OSS/BSS solution for marketplace, storefront, subscription management, service catalog, ticketing, monitoring, usage collection, rating, recurring billing, and reporting with complete workflow orchestration and process automation.

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.